Harvard University. Corporation. Records of land and property owned by Harvard University, 1643-1835: an inventory
Records of land and property owned by Harvard University, 1643-1835
- X. Framingham (Danforth Estate), 1698-1779, .10 cubic feet (4 legal folders and 3 oversize folders)
  - Lease of multiple lots in Framingham for 999 years, Thomas Danforth to John Whitney, March 25, 1699, UAI 15.750 Oversize cabinet, Folder 6
    Signed in the presence of John Fiske, Joseph Buckminster, and Isaac Bowen. Danforth leased multiple lots, totaling 80+ acres of upland, meadow and swamp to Whitney and his heirs and assigns. Danforth died later in the year this lease was signed and bequeathed the lands and rents to Harvard. Note on verso indicates that Edward Holyoke sold the land to Daniel Haven on Aug. 11, 1767, on behalf of the Harvard Corporation.
  - Document concerning Thomas Danforth’s leases in Framingham being given to Harvard College(?), Oct. 21, 1724, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 77
    This document is almost completely illegible and its contents are thus not clear. Verso reads: ”This paper was presented to ye Corporation by ye Hon[orab]le Col. Foxcroft Oct. 21, 1724.”
  - Order that John Whitney and Moses Haven pay rents for Framingham property to Harvard, according to Thomas Danforth’s will, Dec. 1, 1726, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 78
    Francis Foxcroft was the executor of Thomas Danforth’s estate, and this order was to inform two tenants on land in Framingham owned by Danforth that they would, henceforward, pay their rent to the Harvard treasurer (per Danforth’s will). Signed by Foxcroft, Thaddeus Mason, and Christopher Bridge.
  - Memorandum about Hopkinton and Framingham lands belonging to Harvard, ca. 1750?, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 79
  - Daniel Haven’s receipt for Jan. 31, 1764 payment to Thomas Hubbard for lease of three farms in Framingham, May 27, 1779, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 80
    Haven apparently bought the leases of Isaac Bowin, Benjamin Whitney, and John Whitney. Note on verso: “Sold to Natha Biglow.”
- XI. Lunenburg, 1729-1756, .04 cubic feet (4 legal folders)
  Records in this series pertain to a 250 acre lot in Lunenburg, Massachusetts granted to Harvard by the General Court in 1719. One document refers to another lot of 250 acres granted by the General Court on the same occasion, in an unnamed town that was Townsend, Massachusetts (See Series XIII). The series includes a copy of the General Court's vote; a plan and description of the lot created by surveyor Nathan Heywood; Heywood's bills for the survey work; and a lease of a portion of the land to Benjamin Wetherbee.
  - Vote of the General Court to establish two new towns (Lunenburg and Townsend) and to grant 250 acres in each town to Harvard, Nov. 4, 1719, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 81
  - Plan and description of College land at Lunenburg, created by surveyor Nathan Heywood, Dec. 26, 1729, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 82
    Signed by Nathan Heywood, Josiah Willard, Edward Hartwell, and Jonathan Willard.
  - Two bills for surveying and recording the College land in Lunenburg, Aug. 10, 1730, and receipt of payment, Aug. 19, 1730, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 83
    Solomon Prentice accepted the payment, on behalf of the Committee of Lunenburg.
  - Lease of thirty acres of College land in Lunenburg to Benjamin Wetherbee, July 13, 1756, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 84
    This lease was highly conditional. Not only was Wetherbee expected to fence the land and to monitor surrounding lands for trespassers, but he was to give up the land without protest if Harvard decided to sell the property while he was living on it. Signed by Benjamin Wetherbee, Sam Wuth, and Sam Johnson.
- XII. Narragansett farm, 1696-1829, 1.12 cubic feet (2 document boxes and 6 oversize folders)
  On June 24, 1696, Chief Justice of the Province of Massachusetts Bay Samuel Sewall (1652-1730) and his wife, Hannah Hull Sewall, donated a 500 acre farm “at Petaquomscot in Narragansett Country,” Rhode Island to Harvard, specifying that the income generated from tenant farmers be used for "the support and education at the College, of youths, whose parents may not be of sufficient ability to maintain them there, especially such as should be sent from Petaquamscot, English or Indians." This farm constituted a portion of a larger tract of land in Narragansett country purchased by John Hull (Hannah's father) and others in 1657, in what was called the Petaquamscot purchase. Harvard leased the Narragansett farm to a series of tenant farmers, including Stephen Gardner, Paske Austin, Peter Reynolds, Peter Reynolds, Jr., Palmer Cleaveland, Nicholas Gardner, and Huling Gardiner. On January 4, 1809, an auction was held in which rights to remove the timber from individual portions of the farm were sold. On June 23, 1827, another auction was held, and the lots themselves were sold, ending Harvard's involvement with the land.
  Bicknell, Thomas Williams. The History of the State of Rhode Island and Providence Plantations. New York: The American Historical Society, 1920.
  This series contains records related to the Narragansett farm owned by Harvard. It includes the original deed of gift for the farm, as well as abundant correspondence with and about the farm's tenants, Stephen Gardner, Paske Austin, Peter Reynolds, Peter Reynolds, Jr., Palmer Cleaveland, Nicholas Gardner, and Huling Gardiner. It should be noted that there are variations in the spelling of several of these men's names, including Reynolds/Raynolds and Gardner/Gardiner. The farm was divided into smaller tracts of land, and thus often occupied by several tenants at once. This series also includes correspondence with local agents (most often lawyers) whom Harvard hired to manage the farm's affairs. These agents were Francis Willett, Joseph Denison, Rouse J. Helm, David Leonard Barnes, and Thomas Burgess, and their correspondence with the College Treasurer often provides valuable information about the tenants, their use of the land, and financial matters.
  According to the tenants' leases, they were required to do the following: to plant apple orchards on the farm (with trees paid for by Harvard) and to prevent horned cattle from damaging the orchards; to clear a given number of acres each year, with the sometime assistance of goats supplied by the College; to pay taxes on the land; to keep the dwelling houses in good repair; to build fences, specifically "good four rail or Virginia fence," and - of course - to pay their rent. The tenants often failed to meet these requirements, though, and many of the records in this series concern those failures. One tenant, Peter Reynolds, was particularly lax in paying his rent, and in 1755 the College had him sent to jail as a consequence. There were also difficulties in receiving a particular rent payment, made in 1780 in the form of "a thousand weight of cheese," because of an embargo against its leaving Rhode Island. Nicholas Gardner, the tenant trying to transport this cheese to Cambridge, explained that "the state [of Rhode Island] hath an Imbargo on the same that it canot be carried out of the State as you will be informed by a coppy of the act of a sembly published in Newspaper which I send you."
  The records in this series also contain information about the depreciation of paper currency, and the challenges of receiving payments in various currencies ("Spanish Mexico milled dollars," Sterling, "lawfull money," Continental dollars, etc.) whose stability fluctuated. There also appears to have been concern about counterfeit money. In addition, there are numerous reports on the condition of the farm which include information about the crops being grown, including Indian corn, rye, oats, tobacco, peaches, and apples, and the livestock being raised, which included horned cattle, horses, goats, and sheep. In addition, there are extensive records related to the January 4, 1809 auction of rights to the farm's timber and the June 23, 1827 auction of the land itself.
  - Deed of gift of Narragansett farm from Samuel Sewall and Hannah Sewall to the President and Fellows of Harvard College, June 24, 1696, UAI 15.750 Box 9, Folder 16
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Henry Flynt about Narragansett farm, Jan. 3, 1731, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 12
  - Letter from Edward Hutchinson to Benjamin Wadsworth about Stephen Gardner, March 18, 1731, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 13
  - Henry Flynt’s description of Narragansett farm, July 15, 1731, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 85
  - Memorandum about Stephen Gardner, tenant at Narragansett farm, March 18, 1732, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 86
  - Letters from Francis Willett to Edward Hutchinson about Narragansett farm, June 3, 1732 and Aug. 10, 1732, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 14
    The first letter mentions that a Mrs. Coles is leasing part of Narragansett farm; the second letter explains that Paske Austin hopes to lease the other portion of the farm.
  - Lease of Narragansett farm to Paske Austin, March 25, 1733, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 24
    The lease is unsigned.
  - Articles of agreement, draft of lease, and description of house to be built for Paske Austin, tenant of Narragansett farm, October 26, 1733, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 87
  - Memorandum of agreement with Job Tripp to build a dwelling house on Narragansett farm, Nov. 5, 1733, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 88
  - Vote of President and Fellows appointing a committee to lease part of Narragansett farm to Peter Reynolds, August 18, 1735, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 89
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Henry Flynt recommending Peter Reynolds as a tenant, August 2, 1735, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 90
    A long addendum was made to the document on August 5, 1735 (by Flynt?).
  - Minutes of Agreement with Peter Reynolds regarding tenancy at Narragansett farm, Sept. 11, 1735, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 91
    Addendum made to the document on October 24, 1738 notes that Reynolds built his house 4 feet wider than had been agreed.
  - Bond of Peter Reynolds, Sept. 12, 1735, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 92
    Signed by Peter Reynolds, Rebekah Williams and David Collson.
  - Memorandum regarding Palmer Cleaveland’s wish to lease land on Narragansett farm, April 12, 1736, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 93
    Indicates that Cleaveland requested funds to purchase twenty goats. Addendum made to the document on March 30, 1737.
  - Statement of Benjamin Wadsworth about the use of income from Narragansett farm, Dec. 1, 1735, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 94
  - Lease of Narragansett farm to Peter Reynolds, Sept. 12, 1736, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 15
    Signed by Peter Reynolds, David Collson, and Rebekah Williams.
  - Memorandum about Mr. Gold’s wish to lease land on Narragansett farm, Dec. 21, 1736, UAI 15.750 Box 4, Folder 95
  - Proposal from Palmer Cleaveland regarding the use of land on Narragansett farm, July 2, 1737, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 1
    Verso contains two addenda from October 27, 1738.
  - Meeting minutes regarding Palmer Cleaveland’s potential tenancy at Narragansett farm, Nov. 1, 1737, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 2
  - Letter from Palmer Cleaveland to Henry Flynt, Dec. 24, 1737, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 3
    Verso contains notes from President Fellows’ meeting held Nov. 7, 1738 about Cleaveland and Reynolds. It was agreed to make Cleaveland’s lease several years longer, per his request in this letter.
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Henry Flynt about Palmer Cleaveland’s tenancy at Narragansett farm, January 22, 1738, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 4
  - Letter from Palmer Cleaveland to Henry Flynt, May 29, 1738, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 5
    Addenda, Nov. 10, 1738
  - Extract of Harvard Corporation vote about Narragansett farm, copied on Oct. 27, 1738, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 6
    The vote was made on October 10, 1733. Verso contains two addenda about Cleaveland’s tenancy, dated June 16, 1738 and Oct. 27, 1738.
  - Lease of Narragansett farm to Palmer Cleaveland, Nov. 25, 1738, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 25
    Signed by Palmer Cleaveland, Francis Willett, and Samuel Watson.
  - Bond of Palmer Cleaveland, unsigned, Nov. 25, 1738(?), UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 7
  - Memorandum about Palmer Cleaveland’s tenancy at Narragansett farm, ca. 1738, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 8
    Verso contains letter from Timothy Cutler to an unknown recipient, dated Nov. 15, 1738.
  - Requests from Peter Reynolds concerning Narragansett farm, ca. 1738, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 9
    Reynolds did not date his request, but addenda on the verso made on Oct. 27, 1738 and Nov. 14, 1738 make it clear that the request was written prior to those dates.
  - Agreement of the committee that Edward Holyoke and Henry Flynt should visit Narragansett farm, Sept. 5, 1739, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 10
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Henry Flynt, Sept. 10, 1739, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 11
  - Manuscript copy of agreements with Peter Reynolds and Palmer Cleaveland, Sept. 1739, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 12
  - Agreement of committee regarding leases and bonds of Peter Reynolds and Palmer Cleaveland, Oct. 9, 1739, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 13
  - Extension of lease of Narragansett farm to Peter Reynolds, Oct. 18, 1739, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 14
    This was a three-year extension of the lease Reynolds already had and was to take effect on March 25, 1750; it applied to the years 1750-1753. Signed by Peter Reynolds, Ruth Thomas, Hannah Gould, and Francis Willett ("Justice of the Quorum"). An annotation from Willett indicates that the lease wasn’t actually signed until Oct. 14, 1740.
  - Manuscript copy of letter from Edward Holyoke to Francis Willett, Nov. 22, 1739, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 15
  - Bond of Palmer Cleaveland and John Cleaveland, Sept. 12, 1740, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 16
    Signed by Palmer Cleaveland, John Cleaveland, Dan Coggeshall and John Congdon.
  - Bond of Peter Reynolds, William Tanner, and Peter Reynolds, Jr., Oct. 14, 1740, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 17
    Signed by Peter Reynolds, Peter Reynolds, Jr. ("a weaver"), William Tanner (“a yeoman”), as well as Ruth Thomas, Hannah Gould, and Francis Willett ("Justice of the Quorum").
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Henry Flynt about Peter Reynold’s wish to transfer his lease, Oct. 29, 1744, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 18
    Reynolds claimed he was no longer physically capable of maintaining the farm; he wanted to assign his lease to “an honest industrious man” named John Dawley.
  - Letter from Henry Flynt to Francis Willett, ca. Nov. 1744, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 19
    The verso contains an unrelated letter to Edward Holyoke from Roland Cotton, dated Nov. 9, 1744, so this letter was presumably written after that.
  - Agreement of the committee that Henry Flynt should visit, inspect, and report on Narragansett farm, July 1745, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 20
  - Henry Flynt’s report on Narragansett farm, 1745, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 21
  - Belcher Hancock’s report on Narragansett farm, May 1, 1748 and Dec. 20, 1748, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 22
    Verso contains a May 23, 1748 letter from Anthony Bracke(?) to Matthew Pate of Newport.
  - Agreement to lease additional land on Narragansett farm to Palmer Cleaveland, Dec. 28, 1748, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 23
  - Belcher Hancock’s report on Narragansett farm, July 14, 1750, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 24
  - Committee report on Narragansett farm, written by Joseph Mayhew and Thomas Marsh, May 4, 1752, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 25
  - Manuscript copy of a letter from Thomas Hubbard to Francis Willett about Peter Reynolds, Aug. 31, 1752, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 26
  - Memorandum about Peter Reynolds and Narragansett farm, ca. 1752, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 27
  - Memorandum regarding work to be done on Narragansett farm, ca. 1752, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 28
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Edward Holyoke about Peter Reynolds, Jan. 19, 1753, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 29
  - Letter from Thomas Hubbard to Edward Holyoke about Narragansett farm, March 9, 1753, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 30
    Hubbard suggests that in the future, when renting out the farm, they should ask to be paid in “either Sterling or lawfull money for whenever I deal with a Rd Islander, I imagine myself to be dealing with a lawless creature... therefore love to prevent disputes.”
  - Letter from Edward Holyoke to Francis Willett about Narragansett farm, March 9, 1753, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 31
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Edward Holyoke about Narragansett farm, March 20, 1753, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 32
  - Notes regarding conversation with Francis Willett about Narragansett farm, May 10, 1753, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 33
    Document is written almost entirely in shorthand.
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Edward Holyoke about Nicholas Gardner, May 23, 1753, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 34
    Nicholas Gardner was the new tenant, who replaced Reynolds. He was given an eight-year lease
  - Memorandum about Narragansett Farm, May-Nov. 1753, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 35
  - Draft of lease and calculations regarding a dwelling house on Narragansett farm, Dec. 1753, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 36
    This lease was to be for eight years and was presumably for Nicholas Gardner, although the name is left blank on the lease.
  - Memorandum about Peter Reynolds and Narragansett farm, ca. 1753?, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 37
  - Lease of Narragansett farm to Nicholas Gardner, Jan. 31, 1754, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 38
    Signed by Edward Holyoke, Nathan Holt, Amos Sampson, and Samuel Danforth.
  - Draft of lease of Narragansett farm to Nicholas Gardner, March 25, 1754, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 39
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Edward Holyoke about Narragansett farm, April 6, 1754, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 40
  - Letter from Edward Holyoke to Thomas Hubbard about Narragansett farm, May 15, 1754, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 41
  - Joseph Mayhew’s account of a visit with Peter Reynolds, who was in jail, and of the condition of Narragansett farm, March-April 1755, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 42
    Mayhew describes the comfort and lax security of the jail, "liberties so unusual to be given to Prisoners, in any other government, but that of Rhode Island." Reynolds had been sent to jail for non-payment of his debts to Harvard, and Mayhew visited him there to try to negotiate the settlement. He reports having little success, as Reynolds was apparently quite stubborn.
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Thomas Hubbard about Narragansett farm, Sept. 4, 1755, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 43
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Thomas Hubbard about Palmer Cleaveland, May 9, 1757, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 44
  - Statement of Nicholas Gardner’s account with Harvard College, July 27, 1757, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 45
  - Memorandum about Nicholas Gardner’s account and Francis Willett, July 1757, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 46
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Thomas Hubbard about Palmer Cleaveland, Sept. 23, 1757, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 47
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Thomas Hubbard about Palmer Cleaveland, Nov. 10, 1758, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 48
  - Manuscript copy of letter from Thomas Hubbard to Francis Willett about Palmer Cleaveland, Nov. 16, 1758, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 49
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Thomas Hubbard about Palmer Cleaveland, Feb. 12, 1759, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 50
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Thomas Hubbard about Palmer Cleaveland, Oct. 24, 1759, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 51
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Thomas Hubbard about Palmer Cleaveland and Mr. Hammand, March 13, 1760, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 52
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Thomas Hubbard about Palmer Cleaveland and Mr. Hammand, June 12, 1760, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 53
  - Nicholas Gardner’s agreement regarding a portion of land at Narragansett farm, June 29, 1760, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 54
  - Memorandum about Narragansett farm, 1760(?), UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 55
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Thomas Hubbard about Narragansett farm, Aug. 4, 1761, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 56
  - Lease of Narragansett farm to Nicholas Gardner, Feb. 10, 1762, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 57
    Signed by Nicholas Gardner, Francis Willett, and John Gardner.
  - Bond of Nicholas Gardner, Feb. 10, 1762, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 58
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Thomas Hubbard about financial matters, Feb. 16, 1762, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 59
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Thomas Hubbard about Nicholas Gardner, May 29, 1762, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 60
  - Nicholas Gardner’s agreement to build ten rods of stone wall on Narragansett farm, Oct. 19, 1762, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 61
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Thomas Hubbard about Narragansett farm, Oct. 21, 1762, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 62
  - Letter from Thomas Hubbard to Francis Willett about Narragansett farm, April 11, 1768, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 63
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Thomas Hubbard about Nicholas Gardner, April 20, 1768, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 64
  - Extension of Nicholas Gardner’s lease of Narragansett farm, May 28, 1768, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 65
    Signed by Francis Willett.
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Thomas Hubbard about Narragansett farm, June 3, 1768, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 66
  - Letter from Samuel Fayerweather to unknown recipient about Narragansett farm, March 4, 1769, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 67
    Samuel Fayerweather wrote this letter on behalf of Francis Willett, who was too ill to write. The letter concerns the renewal of Nicholas Gardner’s lease, which Willett recommended.
  - Letter from Samuel Fayerweather to unknown recipient about Narragansett farm, March 29, 1769, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 68
    This letter was also written by Samuel Fayerweather on behalf of Francis Willett; it appears to have been delivered to the recipient in person by Nicholas Gardner.
  - Letter from Francis Willett to Thomas Hubbard about Nicholas Gardner, June 6, 1769, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 69
  - Letter from Edward Deake to Andrew Eliot, reporting on Narragansett farm, March 3, 1775, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 16
  - Letter from S. Hall to the Harvard Corporation reporting on Narragansett farm, July 21, 1778, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 70
  - Letter from Joseph Denison to Ebenezer Storer about Narragansett farm, March 8, 1779, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 71
    Denison replaced Francis Willett as the local representative of Harvard in regards to the farm.
  - Letter from Joseph Denison to Ebenezer Storer(?) about Narragansett farm, March 2, 1780, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 72
  - Letter from Nicholas Gardner to Ebenezer Storer about Narragansett farm, March 26, 1780, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 73
    In this letter, Gardner explains that he has “a thousand weight of cheese to discharge the rent” but that he cannot send it to Cambridge because “the state [of Rhode Island] hath laid an Imbargo on the same that it canot be carried out of the State as you will be informed by a coppy of the act of a sembly published in Newspaper which I send you.”
  - Letter from Joseph Denison to Ebenezer Storer about Narragansett farm, April 8, 1780, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 74
  - Letter from Joseph Denison to Ebenezer Storer about disposition of cheese, June 20, 1780, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 75
  - William Elliott’s receipt of payment for freight of cheese, July 6, 1780, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 76
  - Account of sale of cheese received as rent for Narragansett farm, Oct. 9, 1780, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 77
    Signed by Peter Sigourney.
  - Letter from Joseph Denison to Ebenezer Storer about Narragansett farm, March 29, 1781, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 78
    Contains information about the exchange rate between Continental dollars and “hard dollars,” as it related to the Gardner’s cheese and the fair cost of renting the farm.
  - Statement of Joseph Dension’s account with Harvard College, Nov. 22, 1781, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 79